talkphotography.co.uk 2016-06-24

# * Privacy Policy | Talk Photography

#### Privacy policy

### About Talk Photography

Talk Photography is owned and maintained by [Slack Media Ltd](https://www.slackmedia.co.uk/).

### Our commitment

Slack Media Ltd values your privacy and your desire to protect your personal information. This page is to explain to you the type of information we collect about you, why we collect it, and how that information is used.   
If you have any questions about this privacy policy you can contact us via email : [admin@talkphotography.co.uk](mailto:admin@talkphotography.co.uk), or via our Contact Us page. Our postal address is available on request.

### What information we collect

Slack Media Ltd collects and stores the following types of information about you. 

  * Information about your computer, including IP address, browser type, operating system and screen resolution. 
  * If you are registering, or are registered as a member, we also collect the following information.
    * Compulsory information provided by you, for the purposes of registering as a member, including email address and date of birth.
    * Voluntary information provided by you and entered into your user profile, either at time of registration, or later. This includes your real name, location, occupation and biography, amongst others.
    * Your preferences and customised options as to how you wish the site to 'look' and 'feel'.
  * Other voluntary information we collect, is any information entered by you into posts and threads on the forum.

### Why we collect this information

The information about your computer is collected to assist us in compiling our website visitor statistics. These enable us to adapt and maintain Talk Photography for the enjoyment of the majority of our visitors. With the exception of the IP address, the information about your computer is never linked to any personally identifiable information or your site account.   
Your IP address is collected to allow us to enforce our site rules, detect duplicate registrations, and to assist you should you have any problems or queries (technical or otherwise) while using our site.   
The voluntary information you enter into your profile is to nurture our community aspect.   
Your email address is required by us to ensure that we have a line of contact with a real person, and to assist us in enforcing our forum rules and to detect duplicate registrations.   
Your date of birth is required so we can detect members under the age of 18, and restrict their site access accordingly.

### Cookies

The Talk Photography website makes use of browser cookies. A cookie is a small file of information which is placed on your computer with information relevant to your visit to our website. This is used to enable us to distinguish you as a registered member (if you are), and to enable you to take part in and access areas of our website which would otherwise be restricted. It also allows us to offer you a more personalised experience by way of applying your preferences and options to your visit.   
We also use cookies that store your username (but not password unless you explicitly allow it to), to enable you to return to our site quicker on your next visit and stay logged in.   
talkphotography.co.uk also uses third party advertisements provided via Google.com and other schemes such as Skimlinks and/or Viglinks.   
These advertisements and schemes may also place cookies on your computer that may store and track your computer information (for example IP address, browser and ISP). These third-party cookies cannot read your Talk Photography information (such as your email address or profile). You may disable either our cookies, and/or our third party advertisers cookies in your browser preferences. If you disable the talkphotography.co.uk cookies, this may affect your ability to interact with various functions of our site (particularly those that require you to be logged in).

### How we use your information

Your voluntary personal information (your location, occupation, biography etc) is stored in your user profile, and is viewable by any registered member.   
Your date of birth will be used to automatically send you a short congratulatory email on your birthday.   
Your email address will be used to notify you of various website changes. These include (but are not limited to), replies after you in a thread, notification of a private message by another member. These notifications are mostly opt-in, and can all be turned off via your user control panel.   
We will periodically send out an email newsletter to you. This can be opted out of too via your user control panel.   
We will also use your email address for our site staff to communicate with you any updates, problems or information about your account.

### Sharing of your information

Your date of birth is kept private unless you change your options to allow it to be shown to other site visitors.   
By default your email address is not visible to other members, and at the moment there is no option to override this.   
Your contact details (including email address) will never be sold to a third party.

If you are involved in a classifieds transaction and the other member has tried to (but cannot) contact you via the forum PM system, then we may pass your email address to them privately. This is only ever done after a request by the other member and each situation is decided on its individual merits.   
Our classifieds section is based on trust, and in order to maintain that trust we aim to help protect our members against any possible fraudulent transactions. To help us with this, we publish on the forums, the details of those we consider 'bad traders'. A bad trader is someone who has not met their obligation in a classifieds transaction with another member, often resulting in the other member suffering a financial loss. These details are published on the forums in accordance with our site terms and conditions (often referred to as 'Rules'), and usually only after the member in question has been banned from the classifieds section.   
This is only ever done as a last resort when other avenues and options have failed.

### Opting out, and consent

If you are a registered member, you may only opt-out of receiving our newsletters, or any other forum notifications by modifying your user preferences.   
However, we may still contact you with what we consider are important updates or notifications regarding the site or your account, or queries regarding your conduct or activity on the site.   
You may, at any time, remove any voluntary information you enter into your user control panel, except your valid email address and date of birth. These are required to keep your site membership active.   
We may delete your site account on request. Please use the Contact Us facility of the site to do so. If you wish, you may remove ALL information from your profile yourself. However, please note that your account will become restricted if you remove your valid email address, so remove this information last.

### Advertisements and Skimlinks/Viglinks

Like many other internet sites, the talkphotography.co.uk website contains 'Affiliate links' to assist in raising revenue to help fund the site.   
To assist us in this we use a tested and trusted technology from both Skimlinks.com and Viglinks.com. (Usually only one of these is active at any one time).   
Members often post links to external sites, such as online shops and merchants. When you click on one of these links, Skimlinks/Viglinks analyses the URL and if applicable automatically converts it to include the Slack Media Ltd affiliate ID.   
Should you then make a purchase from the online shop, this generates a small payment to Slack Media Ltd from the relevant affiliate scheme.   
This is at absolutely no extra cost or inconvenience to you, and is almost completely transparent.

### Google Adsense and the DoubleClick DART Cookie

As an advertisement provider, Google uses cookies to serve adverts on this site. The use of DART cookies by Google enables them to serve relevant adverts to you based on your previous visits to this and other websites.   
You may opt out of the DART cookies by visiting the Google Privacy Center at the following url [www.google.com/privacy_ads.html](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). Tracking of users through the DART cookies are subject to Google's own privacy policies.
